<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Nylira Articles</title>
 <link href="http://nylira.com/en/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://nylira.com"/>
 <updated>2013-07-09T03:34:30+08:00</updated>
 <id>http://nylira.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Peng Zhong</name>
   <email>peng@nylira.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>On PRISM</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/on-prism"/>
   <updated>2013-06-11T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/on-prism</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve created a site to help you opt of PRISM at &lt;a href=&quot;https://prism-break.org&quot;&gt;prism-break.org&lt;/a&gt;. Below are interview questions I was asked by an Associated Press reporter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;In broad terms, why did you start prism-break.org? A Slate story you linked to on the site said &quot;last week activists launched&quot; the site — did you do this in collaboration with others or by yourself?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After The Guardian broke Edward Snowden&#39;s story about PRISM, I decided that I needed to free my data from the cloud. While it&#39;ll be impossible to confirm whether if Google or Dropbox actually removes my data from their servers, I can at least be proactive and limit future damage by moving away to self-hosted services. I started researching the various options, and found out that there was really no solid guide on how to transition away from proprietary web services. I purchased the prism-break.org domain when I realized that there are a lot of people in the same situation as I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prism Break started as a text file on my computer. I launched the first version of the site over the course of several hours on June 10th. I initially posted prism-break.org on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1g1sxa/how_to_opt_out_of_prism_the_nsas_global_data/&quot;&gt;Reddit&#39;s /r/technology subreddit&lt;/a&gt;, and the site been spreading entirely by word of mouth since then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I started Prism Break on my own, I have gotten lots of great feedback, edits, and translations over the last week from the community. I&#39;ve been implementing the more mature and robust software suggestions onto the site. The codebase for the site is also open source, non-copyrighted, and publicly available on Github (https://github.com/nylira/prism-break). I&#39;m very thankful to all those who&#39;ve contributed thus far to the current state of Prism Break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What has the response been? I saw on Twitter that you passed 200K visits — have you seen other indicators of people changing their computing habits?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The response has been far stronger than I had anticipated. I went to sleep after posting PRISM Break on Reddit, expecting upvotes in the double digits. I woke up to find PRISM Break one of the most popular submissions on the site, and an email from the Free Software Foundation inqiring about my future objectives with the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I don&#39;t have indicators of people changing their computing habits, I do have PRISM Break anonymized record of outgoing clicks. It shows that GNU/Linux, Bitmessage, Tor Browser Bundle, DuckDuckGo, OwnCloud, and OpenStreetMap are among the most popular topics among visitors. I don&#39;t have any hard statistics past this point though. You&#39;ll have to get the download data from the software websites themselves. Based on many PRISM Break discussions I&#39;ve read though, quite a number of people are switching out Google for DuckDuckGo or Startpage, and many of them considering switching their Operating System to GNU/Linux. It&#39;s a start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Have you changed any of your own computing or other habits as a result of the NSA revelations? If so, what and why?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have switched my operating system from Apple OS X to Trisquel GNU/Linux. While Trisquel itself isn&#39;t particularly focused on security, the GNU/Linux open source ecosystem is much more conducive to privay and security. Apple&#39;s proprietary walled-garden means any number of tracking codes can be in your software without your knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve also switched from Google Search -&gt; Startpage, Google Chrome -&gt; Firefox, Dropbox -&gt; Git Annex Assistant, Google Talk to Adium (w/ OTR), Skype -&gt; Jitsi, and Google Analytics -&gt; Piwik. It&#39;s been a surprisingly easy change in every category so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Do you think the knowledge of these spying programs are reframing the way people think about privacy and how they go about their business? A lot of people are talking about changing their habits — do you think people will actually do it?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s easier to talk to than to act. People are lazy, and online privacy is difficult right now. Most of us have grown so reliant on Google and Facebook that these applications become nearly impossible to replace. Even if you&#39;re not personally adverse to change, your company or social network may not feel the same way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most people, Facebook is going to be the most diffcult app to remove from their life. Facebook has a very strong networking effect. How will you ask your prospective employer to make a new account on your self-hosted social network? How about a new friend? There&#39;s no easy answer to this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I&#39;m hoping that people will realize that PRISM is no ordinary privacy breach. Those who understand that every word they type on Facebook or every word they say on Skype may be permanently recorded by the NSA will definitely look into encrypting their communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Between chat, email encryption web browsing and currency, there are a lot of different bases to cover for people. Which do you think are the most important for people concerned about unwanted snooping?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communication is the most important part that needs to be encrypted. Unfortunately, email, even encrypted with GPG, is difficult to keep private. Your email provider has the metadata of your mail (who&#39;s sending to whom), and if your encryption key is breached even once, all your previous correspondence is compromised. I advise treating email as a public forum and using a messaging client with off-the-record (OTR) encryption for sensitive communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I advise visitors to research the options presented (and options unpresented) and come to their own conclusion as to which combination of software serves their needs best. There&#39;s no one all-encompassing solution for online privacy at the moment, but I&#39;m sure teams around the world are working hard on implementing just that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How long did it take you to make the switches you described, from Apple OSX to Trisquel GNU/Linux and Google to Startpage, etc., all the way down the line? How many hours do you think you&#39;ve put into this?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn&#39;t take long to make the switch to software. It&#39;s doable in a couple hours, depending on your internet connection speed. The time-consuming part is figuring software replacements that are free, polished, and unlikely to leak your information to third parties. This has taken me over a hundred hours so far, and this is the freely available information prism-break.org.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Now that you&#39;ve made these changes, how confident/comfortable are you about your privacy? Obviously it&#39;s got to be much better than before, but that&#39;s certainly different than feeling at ease or something close to it.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m feeling much more comfortable about my privacy after the switch. I definitely think my data is at least an order of magnitude safer than when I was using OS X and Chrome. Of course, I&#39;ll constantly be looking for easier and better ways to safeguard my privacy, and I&#39;ll update PRISM Break accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;In terms of Facebook and other social networks, do you think you&#39;ll use them less or change your approach to status updates and photos?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve always been concerned about my online footprint. Even before PRISM became public knowledge, the vast amount of data a Google search could pull up on someone is startling, and incredibly difficult to remove. People should be careful of what they say in a public forum, because it will follow them for the rest of their lives. With the advent of Google Glass, even offline conversations may be forever etched in digital memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Cheeky question: Did you by chance call the site Prism-break as a play on the Fox show &quot;Prison Break&quot;? How&#39;d you come up with the name.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;PRISM Break&quot; came up almost immediately as I brainstormed the various options for a domain name. I was really surprised it wasn&#39;t taken yet. Fox&#39;s show &quot;Prison Break&quot; is on my to-watch list, so that may have influenced it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Last comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prism Break has only been in existence for a little over a week. It&#39;s a constant work in progress, and updates are pushed live every day. There are bound to be mistakes, but I&#39;ll do my best to fix them quickly. I advise not taking Prism Break as the authoritative resource on privacy, but as a starting point for further exploration into freedom and anonymity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re interested in contributing, please do! The source files are available here: https://github.com/nylira/prism-break.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Effectiveness</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/effectiveness"/>
   <updated>2012-09-05T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/effectiveness</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As powerful as &lt;a href=&quot;http://learnboost.github.com/stylus/&quot;&gt;Stylus&lt;/a&gt; is, it&#39;s easy to go overboard with mixins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CSS proprocessor Stylus makes it &lt;a href=&quot;http://nylira.com/stylus-the-revolutionary-successor-to-css/&quot;&gt;incredibly easy&lt;/a&gt; to define transparent mixins. With symbols like $ and @ stripped away and : and ; being made unnecessary, it&#39;s simple to create your own &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain-specific_language&quot;&gt;DSL&lt;/a&gt; on top of CSS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This capability is immensely powerful when working solo, but it can be difficult to debug for someone else coming into your project. If you work with other designers or hand off code to an external team it&#39;s a good idea to keep mixin usage in Stylus at a bare minimum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this is fine to use on personal projects:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;section.markdown
  aside
    col 4
    ml - c4
    h2
      font2()
      c anchor
      mb x*2
    ul
      ls none

  ul.process
    ml -4c
    clear()
    li
      fl left
      m 0 0 1px 1px
      p
        p x
        m 0
        box c4 - x*2 - 1px
        font2()
        c #ccc
        transition()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In larger projects, it usually pays to be a little less clever:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;section.markdown
  aside
    width: col4
    margin-left: - col4
    h2
      font: font2
      color: anchor
      margin-bottom: m2
    ul
      list-style: none

  ul.process
    ml -4c
    margin-left: - col4
    clearfix()
    li
      float: left
      margin: 0 0 1px 1px
      p
        padding: x
        margin: 0
        height: col4 - x*2 - 1px
        width: col4 - x*2 - 1px
        font: font2
        color: #ccc
        transition()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it takes longer to write out the expanded CSS, doing so will save hours of potential headaches in the future. By being a bit more explicit and a bit less obtuse, the efficiency you lose will be made up several times over if anyone else has to edit your code in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Mobile First</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/mobile-first"/>
   <updated>2012-04-03T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/mobile-first</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Smartphone penetration in the United States is staggering at 48%, up from 18% just two years ago. Among 25-34 year olds, 64% own a smartphone. If you don&#39;t design for mobile, you&#39;ll be left behind by your competitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;One column design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sidebars are often thrown onto a site without much thought. Often, the reasoning comes down to finding something (anything!) to fill the rest of formulaic 960 pixels horizontal space. Maybe it was through some misguided belief that flashy social media icons will rocket the site to the top of Alexa 1000. Tag clouds are cool, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your site requires a sidebar to function, you&#39;re most likely doing something wrong. Either the content is not engaging enough or your navigation needs to be rethought completely. Only dense, database-type sites have a legitimate need for the extra level of navigation. In almost all cases, messy everything-including-the-kitchen-sink navigation sidebars only serves to distract the reader from the content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your users get bored reading content, or interacting with your site, you have some deep-seated issues that no reworking of the sidebar will ever fix. Providing a solution for your user&#39;s wandering eyes does not fix the main problem: poorly presented content. While a sidebar may take 25%-33% of a site&#39;s width, its actual importance is rarely as high as the space it consumes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Designing for the limited real estate of mobile browsers forces you to focus on providing better content. Eschewing the customary sidebar in the beginning of the design process leaves you with no option but to create engaging content that&#39;s able to stand alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Efficiency, efficiency, efficiency&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a mobile site design complete, scaling up for larger screens is a breeze. Since most of the site&#39;s CSS is already defined in ems and percentages, changing font size and element width can instantaneously turn a one-column, tightly focused design into a glorious multi-column mess for larger screens.  There&#39;s no question that media queries add a lot of complexity to your site&#39;s design. Designing mobile first is the only way to take advantage of the way media queries work: a single change in your CSS will be cascaded from 320x480 to 1024x768, 1440x900, and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying to force a desktop site&#39;s CSS into something that will work for mobile is a horrible experience. Desktop websites are messy creations which are never built with scaling in mind. Even if that new desktop-to-mobile conversion your team worked so hard on seems to display properly, updating anything in main site design will break the mobile site all over again. CSS is not well suited for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most sane designers, when faced with a mobile design project for a desktop site, will ask to start from a blank slate. This creates its own set of problems. When this new project done, it&#39;s often ghettoed to http://m.yoursite.com, updated infrequently and only serving a portion of your site&#39;s content. Forcing your mobile users to bolted-on, attaché sites does nothing to improve their disposition to your product. Furthermore, any update you want to make to the site now requires twice the work: once for desktop, and again for mobile. It&#39;s not efficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your ever envision your users viewing your site on a mobile browser, you should strongly consider going mobile first from the beginning. It&#39;ll save you a lot of future headaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The mobile experience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All innovation has been happening in the mobile space. The new iPad screen has near print quality resolution and it&#39;s a joy to behold. Quietly arriving at 2048px &amp;times; 1536px, it blows traditional desktop and latop screens out of the proverbial water. The progress is shocking to think about when the vast majority of LCDs have been topped out at 1920x1080 for nearly a decade. Most users are stuck on less, since they&#39;re on stuck laptops and netbooks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can hold this screen in your hand, and the battery life is better than any laptop. Browsing the web on the iPad is an intimate, emotional experience, with direct one-to-one mapping of finger gestures to smooth, pixel-free interface. It&#39;s intuitive in a way that remotes, keyboards and mice will never be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The bottom line&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don&#39;t future-proof with site by designing with smartphones and tablets in mind, it&#39;ll cost you where it hurts. The mobile web experience is getting better every day, while desktops have been stagnating for over a decade.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Use Soft Delete</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/use-soft-delete"/>
   <updated>2011-06-20T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/use-soft-delete</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Imagine you&#39;re using one of the many todo list apps on the web. You&#39;re feeling great, because you just finished an entire laundry list of tasks. You&#39;ve opened the web app because it&#39;s time for you to delete 15 tasks from your list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see in front of you a massive list of tasks, each with its own discrete &quot;Delete&quot; button. This gives you pause. You click &quot;Delete&quot; on the first of your completed tasks, and a modal window pop up, &quot;Are you sure you want to permanently delete this task?&quot; Yes / No. You sign inwardly and press &quot;Yes&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might do this another 15 times, each time getting more exasperated at the number of hoops you have to jump through to delete a single task. If you&#39;re the less patient type, you may consider give up on the app altogether, because micromanaging tasks is almost more effort than doing the them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Be Like Gmail&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of rudely throwing a modal dialog in your user&#39;s face, consider using Gmail&#39;s method for atomic operations: soft delete. After every action, Gmail displays a nonintrusive status message at the top of the screen. The message tells the user exactly what&#39;s occured--e.g., &quot;This conversation has been archived.&quot;--along with a simple &quot;Undo&quot; link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is soft delete better than modal confirmation windows? For one, this method allows the user to delete faster by skipping a step (the modal middleman). Modal windows are intrusive, workflow-breaking, and force users user to make immediate decisions. Inline undos are far more user-friendly because the entire web app stays usable, instead of being backgrounded. Let&#39;s face it--most deleted files are never wanted back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Taking It Further&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Native OS filesystems allow clicking and dragging to lasso multiple documents in a folder. We&#39;ve used this simple operation on our desktop for years, but it has yet to show up online. Select-lassos could work very well for photography-oriented apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Don&#39;t Delete Anything&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disk-space is cheap, and user whims are fickle. If you can absorb the extra costs, I suggest never permanently deleting anything (unless they delete their account). Give your user a history page, where they can restore the state of everything they&#39;ve ever created or uploaded with your app. When the time comes, they&#39;ll love you for it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Responsive Design & Fluid Grids</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/fluid-grids"/>
   <updated>2011-04-05T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/fluid-grids</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Responsive design is about saving time by making flexible elements that can be reused across multiple devices. Here are some tips I&#39;ve learned while building a &lt;a href=&quot;http://nylira.com/en/projects/#guildwork&quot;&gt;100% fluid site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Make Use of &lt;code&gt;box-sizing: border-box&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the default box model, adding a &lt;code&gt;1px border&lt;/code&gt; to two floats with %-based widths (e.g., 30% and 70%) breaks the layout. Your layout is now now &lt;code&gt;100% + 4px&lt;/code&gt; wide, which is annoyingly unhelpful. Likewise with adding em-based padding. At this point, most practical coders will sigh and add a internal wrapper &lt;code&gt;div&lt;/code&gt; with the border they want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While adding another &lt;code&gt;div&lt;/code&gt; is a fine (albeit hacky) solution, there&#39;s a cleaner way to do it. &lt;code&gt;box-sizing: border-box&lt;/code&gt; is a CSS3 property that fixes the box model for these use cases. Instead of adding padding and borders to the width of the box, it subtracts the same amounts from the space inside of the box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create this mixin in your &lt;a href=&quot;http://nylira.com/stylus-the-revolutionary-successor-to-css&quot;&gt;CSS preprocessor of choice&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;box-sizing(n = border-box)
  -webkit-box-sizing: n
  -moz-box-sizing: n
  box-sizing: n
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you can do the following to your heart&#39;s content:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#announcement
  border-box()
  width 40%
  float left
  border 1px solid #ddd
  padding .75em 1em
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it will only ever be 40% wide. Nice, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Any catches?&lt;/strong&gt; While &lt;code&gt;box-sizing&lt;/code&gt; is a CSS3 property, all browsers which support CSS2.1 will support &lt;code&gt;box-sizing: border-box&lt;/code&gt;. That&#39;s every browser except IE6/7.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;There&#39;s more to the world than &lt;code&gt;float: left&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the early days of CSS-based design, floats were all we had to achieve creative, tableless layouts. They are--and have always been--a hacky and buggy approach, but they&#39;ve also been the best tools we&#39;ve had. Most designers have a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stockholm_syndrome&quot;&gt;Stockholme syndrome&lt;/a&gt; relationship with CSS floats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Float-based layouts are fragile, prone to breaking, and require content clearing in most cases. Don&#39;t even try to do vertical alignment with variable-height floats. You&#39;ll need Javascript for that. The finicky nature of floats makes them ill-suited for the flexible, %-based world of web applications. What other options are there?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;code&gt;display: inline-block&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Useful for more than horizontal layout menus, &lt;code&gt;display: inline-block&lt;/code&gt; can be used in many situations in place of floats. Along with the contents of table cells, inline blocks can be vertically aligned, which leads to intriguing layout possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One caveat to inline blocks is that whitespace in HTML matters. If there&#39;s a space between two &lt;code&gt;display: inline-block&lt;/code&gt; elements, it will render on the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inline blocks are supported by all browsers except IE6/7. There is &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.mozilla.com/webdev/2009/02/20/cross-browser-inline-block/&quot;&gt;a hack available&lt;/a&gt; for IE6/7 support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;code&gt;display: table-cell&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most designers who learned CSS in the days of XHTML validation and web standards instinctively cringe away from anything related to tables. However, the property &lt;code&gt;display: table-cell&lt;/code&gt; does not imply any sort of relation between the content and tabular data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using &lt;code&gt;display: table-cell&lt;/code&gt; turns an element&#39;s display type into a &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;td&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, the original &lt;code&gt;box-sizing: border-box&lt;/code&gt; element. &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;td&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;s will automatically stretch to fill the available horizontal space. It&#39;s a great way to create columns of both variable width and height. Take for example an image next to a column of text. This is possible to do with floats, but when you introduce percentage-based padding, you save time with &lt;code&gt;display: table-cell&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using &lt;code&gt;display: table&lt;/code&gt; will turn all of an element&#39;s direct descendants into &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;td&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; types. If you&#39;re making consistent use of this, consider taking another look at your data: perhaps a real table is in order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Display table/table-cell is supported by all browsers except IE6/7.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Alignment issues?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re using a CSS reset, you&#39;ll most likely encounter alignment issues using either &lt;code&gt;inline-block&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;table-cell&lt;/code&gt;. There&#39;s no need to panic. &lt;a href=&quot;http://meyerweb.com/eric/tools/css/reset/&quot;&gt;Eric Meyer&#39;s Reset CSS&lt;/a&gt; sets all elements to &lt;code&gt;vertical-align: baseline&lt;/code&gt;. That means elements of unequal heights will sit on a baseline instead of hanging from the top like floats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to fix it?&lt;/strong&gt; For &lt;code&gt;display: inline-block&lt;/code&gt;, you&#39;ll need to set its parent element to &lt;code&gt;vertical-align: top&lt;/code&gt;. For &lt;code&gt;display: table-cell&lt;/code&gt;, you&#39;ll need to set it to &lt;code&gt;vertical-align: top&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Avoid Dependency Hell&mdash;VirtualBox Your Projects</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/sandbox"/>
   <updated>2011-03-06T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/sandbox</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As I wrote &lt;a href=&quot;/en/profile&quot;&gt;on my profile&lt;/a&gt;, I manage a separate VirtualBox image for every project I do. What are the benefits of doing so?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Why Virtualize?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avoid dependency hell.&lt;/strong&gt; Ever come back to a project 2-3 months later, and not be able to run it because you&#39;ve already upgraded your libraries to new versions? Debugging these scenarios always take a lot of trial and error. This won&#39;t happen anymore if you freeze the entire development environment along with the project code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Write once, run everywhere&lt;/strong&gt; VirtualBox images are extremely portable. VirtualBox can run on every major operating system, which means you can concievably work anywhere. If you develop on a Windows machine and want to collaborate with someone on OS X, you may run into problems with versioning. If both of you run VirtualBox, the problems all disappear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No more debugging development environments for your developers.&lt;/strong&gt; Related to the point above. Have someone joining your project? Instead of handing them a lengthy and error-prone installation guide, just give them a copy of your VirtualBox image. This saves a ridiculous amount of time and gets them up to speed with zero issues. This benefit of VirtualBox goes up the more contributers you have on your project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ubuntu is closer to a production environment.&lt;/strong&gt; While not exactly the same, a Ubuntu minimal install is much closer to your production server than either Windows or OS X. You&#39;ll be able to solve OS-specific issues early, so your live deployment will be certain to go without a hitch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Preconceived Doubts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Isn&#39;t system performance severely degraded with virtualization?&lt;/strong&gt; This really depends on what you&#39;re working on. For standard web development and design tasks, a virtualized Ubuntu is more than enough power. I&#39;m running this on a 13&quot; MacBook Air with 1.86 GHz Core 2 Duo, and I&#39;ve never had a problem with performance. Compiling might be a bit slower than you&#39;re used to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But it&#39;s such a waste of hard drive space!&lt;/strong&gt; Disk space is cheap these days.  My laptop has a 120 GB HD. That&#39;s probably less storage space than most of you are running. Also, installing with the Ubuntu Minimal CD image means you only install only the basic building blocks of the OS, and download what you need through apt-get. My freshly installed images weigh in 1.5 GBs each. Not bad, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doesn&#39;t it take a long time to setup your dev environment over and over?&lt;/strong&gt; Okay, you&#39;ve got me there. The actual process of installing Ubuntu doesn&#39;t take very long, but getting the right packages and plugins can take a little while. Of course, most of this time is either downloading or compiling, so you&#39;re not actually stuck at the computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doesn&#39;t this take a lot of system memory?&lt;/strong&gt; This is a valid point. If you have under 2 GBs of RAM, performance will definitely be severely degraded with the disc swaps happening every transaction. I&#39;ve never done virtualization with anything less than 4 GBs, but--then again, my Ubuntu images run just fine with 512mb of allotted RAM each. I have two images running at any one time, along with Chrome and Photoshop, and performance has been fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Barebones How-To&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interested in setting up a virtual image? Download these first:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Latest version of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.virtualbox.org/wiki/Downloads&quot;&gt;VirtualBox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://help.ubuntu.com/community/Installation/MinimalCD&quot;&gt;Ubuntu 10.10 64-bit Minimal CD&lt;/a&gt; (15.6MB)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An FTP program--I recommend &lt;a href=&quot;http://panic.com/transmit/&quot;&gt;Transmit&lt;/a&gt; for OS X, &lt;a href=&quot;http://filezilla-project.org/&quot;&gt;FileZilla&lt;/a&gt; otherwise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Install VirtualBox.&lt;/strong&gt; Create a new virtual machine with the default settings for a Ubuntu 64-bit guest OS. 512 MB of ram and 8 GBs of disk space is usually enough. If you have hard drive space to spare, I suggest increasing it to 20 GB. It&#39;s possible to increase the virtual disk size later, but it&#39;s a pain in the ass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Select your new virtual disk and open &quot;Settings.&quot;&lt;/strong&gt; With the Settings window open, click the Network button, and select the Adapter 2 tab. Enable the adapter and choose &#39;Host-only Adapter&#39; from the dropdown menu. This is the first step in giving your host OS access to Ubuntu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boot up the new virtual disk.&lt;/strong&gt; Select the Ubunut Minimal CD .iso you downloaded earlier. Ubuntu is straightfoward to install. When it&#39;s done, login with your new username and password. The first command you should run is &lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install openssh-server&lt;/code&gt;. This will allow SSH and SFTP connections from your host OS to the new guest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Using either vi or nano, open&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;sudo vi /etc/network/interfaces&lt;/code&gt;. Add the following lines to the bottom of the file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;auto eth1
iface eth1 inet static
  address 192.168.56.101
  netmask 255.255.255.0
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Save and exit. Run these commands in the console:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo /etc.d/init/networking restart
sudo ifdown eth1
sudo ifup eth1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&#39;re done. At this point, you should be able to SSH into your new virtual machine from the host OS, or mount the virtual drive with your FTP program.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Stylus, the Revolutionary Successor to CSS</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/stylus-the-revolutionary-successor-to-css"/>
   <updated>2011-03-05T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/stylus-the-revolutionary-successor-to-css</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;About a month ago, &lt;a href=&quot;http://learnboost.github.com/stylus&quot;&gt;Stylus&lt;/a&gt; was released, to little fanfare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s rapidly become my favorite web development tool. Cleaner and more flexible than &lt;a href=&quot;http://sass-lang.com/&quot;&gt;Sass&lt;/a&gt;, Stylus is by far the best CSS preprocessor in the wild. If you&#39;re unfamiliar with preprocessors, just imagine adding variables, functions, and simple arithmetic to CSS. While the additions may seem daunting to beginners, these advanced abstractions are desperately needed by maintainers of complex stylesheets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stylus syntax strips away all colons, semicolons, brackets and most parentheses from regular CSS script. The stark simplicity and elegance of it reminds me of Lisp. What&#39;s more amazing is that Stylus will also accept regular CSS syntax in the same file, reducing possible friction between multiple contributers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s a sample of Stylus, a bit of code that powers this very site:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;section.markdown
  aside
    col 4
    ml - c4
    h2
      alt-font()
      color anchor
      mb m2
    ul
      ls none

  ul.process
    ml -4c
    clear()
    li
      float left
      mar 0 0 1px 1px
      p
        pad m
        mar 0
        square c4 - m2 - 1px
        alt-font()
        color #ccc
        transition()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ll notice that I&#39;ve trimmed down many CSS properties: &lt;code&gt;background&lt;/code&gt; is now &lt;code&gt;bg&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;border-color&lt;/code&gt; is &lt;code&gt;bc&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;margin-left&lt;/code&gt; is &lt;code&gt;ml&lt;/code&gt;, etc. Where I used to use &lt;code&gt;margin: 0 0 2em;&lt;/code&gt; (fewer characters than &lt;code&gt;margin-bottom: 2em;&lt;/code&gt;), I now use &lt;code&gt;mb m2&lt;/code&gt;. The ability to abbreviate properties saves countless amounts of typing, and is reason enough to use Stylus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s the generated CSS by comparison:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;body.profile #content section.profile section.markdown aside {
  width: 320px;
  float: left;
  margin-left: -320px;
}
body.profile #content section.profile section.markdown aside h2 {
  font: bold 13px DIN, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif;
  line-height: 24px;
  text-transform: uppercase;
  -webkit-font-smoothing: antialiased;
  color: #555;
  letter-spacing: 1px;
  color: #ff006a;
  margin: 0 0 16px;
}
body.profile #content section.profile section.markdown aside ul {
  list-style: none;
}
body.profile #content section.profile section.markdown ul.process {
  margin-left: -320px;
}
body.profile #content section.profile section.markdown ul.process:after {
  display: block;
  clear: both;
  content: &quot;&quot;;
}
body.profile #content section.profile section.markdown ul.process li {
  float: left;
  margin: 0 0 1px 1px;
  list-style: none;
}
body.profile #content section.profile section.markdown ul.process li p {
  padding: 16px;
  margin: 0;
  width: 127px;
  height: 127px;
  font: bold 13px DIN, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif;
  line-height: 24px;
  text-transform: uppercase;
  -webkit-font-smoothing: antialiased;
  color: #555;
  letter-spacing: 1px;
  color: #ccc;
  transition: all 0.15s ease;
  -webkit-transition: all 0.15s ease;
  -moz-transition: all 0.15s ease;
  -o-transition: all 0.15s ease;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;dl class=&#39;comparison&#39;&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Stylus Character Count&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;&lt;span&gt;337&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;CSS Character Count&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;&lt;span&gt;1369&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Convinced yet?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have only grazed the surface of what&#39;s possible with the immense power of &lt;a href=&quot;http://learnboost.github.com/stylus/&quot;&gt;Stylus&lt;/a&gt;, and it makes me excited about what I&#39;ll playing with in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Built with git, vi, and Jekyll.</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/hello-jekyll"/>
   <updated>2011-03-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/hello-jekyll</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve migrated this site to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. It seems much easier to use than ExpressionEngine. Of course, you have to be comfortable in text editors and SSH. I can&#39;t stand textareas on the web anymore. It feels so slow and unwieldy. Developer notes follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;March 3rd: Why are post summaries so difficult to pull off? I might have to migrate to Nanoc instead. Update: for the meantime, I&#39;ve decided to not use post summaries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Lightboxes fundamentally broken&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;March 4th: A bit of a tangent, but I&#39;m finding that lightbox scripts are fundamentally broken. The popup windows don&#39;t respond to keyboard shortcuts, and images never show up until they&#39;re 100% loaded. I don&#39;t think script writers understand how nice it is to see part of an image as it loads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It lets you decided whether to finish loading or skip ahead to another picture. A loading GIF doesn&#39;t give any information at all, and just pisses people off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The popup effect also takes you out of the flow of the original article. Usually, a lightboxed image is in reference to something you&#39;re reading. But by clicking on it, you&#39;re effectively hiding the content for the picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s a pain, and that&#39;s why almost all power users open images in new tabs instead. Sure, it can get can confusing trying to link an image tab to what you&#39;re reading. But at least it doesn&#39;t obscure everything.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Intuition is Bullshit</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/intuition-is-bullshit"/>
   <updated>2010-09-04T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/intuition-is-bullshit</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a href=&quot;//oed.com&quot;&gt;OED&lt;/a&gt;, &quot;Intuition is the ability to acquire knowledge without inference or the use of reason.&quot; The &lt;a href=&#39;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intuition_(knowledge)&#39;&gt;Wikipedia article&lt;/a&gt; states that intuition provides us with unjustifiable beliefs (a common ailment of the human brain) and its popularity in supernatural and New Age writings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With such dubious company, why are user experience engineers using &quot;intuitive&quot; to describe the ideal user interface? UX is a science, not an art. There’s no such thing as knowledge without inference or reason. Don’t update your landing page on a whim because it &quot;feels right&quot;. Interface changes need to be backed by hard data, not by your gut instincts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost everything your users do can be tracked, recorded, and graphed by numerous &lt;a href=&quot;//kissmetrics.com&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;//google.com/analytics&quot;&gt;dissemination&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;//mixpanel.com&quot;&gt;services&lt;/a&gt;. Don’t let your graphic designer make these decisions for you: start tracking.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Dropbox Tip No. 1</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/dropbox-tip-1"/>
   <updated>2010-07-05T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/dropbox-tip-1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Want your Vim configuration on another computer? Add this line to your &lt;code&gt;~/.exrc&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;source ~/Dropbox/.exrc
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t have a Dropbox account yet? Get your &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/referrals/NTQ3MDYyNDY5&quot;&gt;own now&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Drawar Bank Entry</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/drawar-bank"/>
   <updated>2010-04-22T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/drawar-bank</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bank mockup designed for &lt;a href=&quot;//www.drawar.com/forums/84/version2000--online-banking-statements/&quot;&gt;Drawar&#39;s Version2.001&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Safari&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the design only completely works in Safari. Such is life when developing on the bleeding edge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//v2.nylira.com/tumblr/posts/bank-safari-big.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//v2.nylira.com/tumblr/posts/bank-safari.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Drawar Bank rendered by Safari 4/Win&quot; title=&quot;Drawar Bank rendered by Safari 4/Win&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Firefox&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firefox 3.6+ gets most of the design correct. but has issues displaying the SVG graph and leaves unsightly white margins between actions. Webkit&#39;s gradient engine (which powers Safari and Chrome) considers borders part of the &quot;background area&quot; when it renders gradients. Firefox&#39;s Gecko engine does not. The discrepancy is quite frustrating when you try to use RGBA/HSLA borders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//v2.nylira.com/tumblr/posts/bank-firefox-big.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//v2.nylira.com/tumblr/posts/bank-firefox.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Drawar Bank rendered by Firefox 3.6/Win&quot; title=&quot;Drawar Bank rendered by Firefox 3.6/Win&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Chrome&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chrome has issues rendering all the CSS3 gradients. There&#39;s also noticeable color banding in Chrome&#39;s gradients, a flaw you don&#39;t see with Safari or Firefox. On the upside, Chrome&#39;s V8 Javascript engine blows every other browser out of the water when it comes to transitions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//v2.nylira.com/tumblr/posts/bank-chrome-big.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//v2.nylira.com/tumblr/posts/bank-chrome.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Drawar Bank rendered by Chrome 5/Win&quot; title=&quot;Drawar Bank rendered by Chrome 5/Win&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;View the &lt;a href=&quot;//v2.nylira.com/p/bank&quot;&gt;bank mockup&lt;/a&gt; live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Sass&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used this as an opportunity to learn more about &lt;a href=&quot;//sass-lang.com/&quot;&gt;Sass&lt;/a&gt;. Sass is a powerful abstraction layer for CSS. It supports variables, mixins, simple arithmetic, and basic looping functions. Writing Sass is essentially writing CSS without brackets or semicolons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the difference in size between the &lt;a href=&quot;//v2.nylira.com/p/bank/css/screen.css&quot;&gt;screen.css&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;//v2.nylira.com/p/bank/css/sass/screen.sass&quot;&gt;screen.sass&lt;/a&gt; files. screen.css is 675 lines long and weighs in at 22.6 KB. screen.sass is 439 lines long and weighs in at 10.1 KB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How is this possible? Most of Sass&#39;s power comes from mixins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;// here&#39;s a simple example
=border-radius($r: 5px)
  border-radius: $r
  -webkit-border-radius: $r
  -moz-border-radius: $r

// call it in screen.sass
+border-radius

// outputs this in screen.css
border-radius: 5px;
-webkit-border-radius: 5px;
-moz-border-radius: 5px;

// if you want to change the border radius, it&#39;s simple
+border-radius(20px)

// outputs
border-radius: 20px;
-webkit-border-radius: 20px;
-moz-border-radius: 20px;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It certainly saves a lot of tedious and repetitive typing. This is only the tip of the iceberg, too. Take a look at my default &lt;a href=&quot;//v2.nylira.com/p/bank/css/sass/_mixins.sass&quot;&gt;mixins.sass&lt;/a&gt; file for more examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;A minor gripe&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only issue I have with Sass is that its compiling speed isn&#39;t as fast as I would like. I&#39;m used to saving my CSS file and then reloading my browser to instantly see my changes. With Sass playing middleman, it can take another second before the changes are reflected in the browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this has piqued your interest, check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://sass-lang.com/&quot;&gt;official Sass website&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Acorn</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/acorn"/>
   <updated>2010-04-02T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/acorn</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Acorn homepage redesign. &lt;a href=&quot;http://flyingmeat.com/acorn&quot;&gt;Acorn&lt;/a&gt; is a Mac image editing program developed by Flying Meat Inc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://v2.nylira.com/p/acorn/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://v2.nylira.com/tumblr/posts/acorn.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Analog Turk</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/analog-turk"/>
   <updated>2010-03-26T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/analog-turk</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Spurred on by &lt;a href=&quot;http://37signals.com/svn/posts/2229-sortfolio-uses-amazons-mechanical-turk&quot;&gt;SvN&#39;s post&lt;/a&gt; about the Amazon Mechanical Turk, this is how I would do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://v2.nylira.com/p/turk&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://v2.nylira.com/tumblr/posts/turk.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Ruby Programming Language</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/ruby-programming-language"/>
   <updated>2010-03-25T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/ruby-programming-language</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I redesigned the Ruby Programming Language homepage. Everything that you see--with the exception of &lt;a href=&quot;http://rubyidentity.org/&quot;&gt;the logo&lt;/a&gt;--consists of just two text files. Cascading stylesheets have come a long way since 1999.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal for the design was to make a monochromatic &amp;amp; image-less layout look visually striking and pretty. I think I&#39;ve mostly succeeded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to say that I really love designing with just a text editor. Photoshop is unwieldy, cumbersome and utterly unsuited for most web design work. Sure, it still comes in handy for more illustration-heavy or textured websites. But for the majority of elegant and clean websites, a text editor works better and is magnitudes faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://v2.nylira.com/p/ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://v2.nylira.com/tumblr/posts/ruby.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Browser notes: this design looks best in Safari/Mac or Firefox 3.6+. I seemed to have broken Chrome&#39;s rendering engine with the gradient spammage. If you use IE or Opera, &lt;a href=&quot;http://v2.nylira.com/portfolio/ruby&quot;&gt;here&#39;s a picture&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://ruby-lang.org&quot;&gt;current ruby-lang.org&lt;/a&gt;, for comparison.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A Cleaner Slashdot</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/a-cleaner-slashdot"/>
   <updated>2010-03-18T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/a-cleaner-slashdot</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Slashdot&#39;s homepage is rather overwhelming. It certainly works well enough on a functional level, but I think it can be done better. This is my attempt to bright things up. Their &lt;a href=&quot;http://slashdot.org&quot;&gt;current website&lt;/a&gt;, for comparison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://v2.nylira.com/p/slashdot&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://v2.nylira.com/tumblr/posts/slashdot.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>
