<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Nylira Articles</title>
 <link href="http://nylira.com/en/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://nylira.com"/>
 <updated>2011-03-05T17:45:41+01:00</updated>
 <id>http://nylira.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Peng Zhong</name>
   <email>peng@nylira.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Stylus, the Future of Web Design</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/stylus-the-future-of-web-design"/>
   <updated>2011-03-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/stylus-the-future-of-web-design</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;About a month ago, &lt;a href=&quot;http://learnboost.github.com/stylus&quot;&gt;Stylus&lt;/a&gt; was released, to little fanfare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has quickly become my favorite web development tool. Cleaner and more flexible than &lt;a href=&quot;http://sass-lang.com/&quot;&gt;Sass&lt;/a&gt;, Stylus is by far the best CSS preprocessor in the wild. If you're unfamiliar with preprocessors, just imagine adding variables, functions, and simple arithmetic to CSS. While the additions may seem daunting to beginners, these advanced abstractions were desperately needed by the maintainers of complex stylesheets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stylus strips away all colons, semicolons, brackets and most parentheses from regular CSS script. The stark simplicity and elegance reminds me of Lisp. What's more amazing is that Stylus will also accept regular CSS syntax in the same file, reducing possible friction between multiple contributers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here's a sample of Stylus, a bit of code that powers this very site:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;section.markdown
  aside
    col 4
    ml - c4
    h2
      alt-font()
      color anchor
      mb  m
    ul
      ls none

  ul.process
    ml -4c
    clear()
    li
      float left
      mar 0 0 1px 1px
      p
        pad m
        mar 0
        square c4 - m2 - 1px
        alt-font()
        color #ccc
        transition()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You'll notice that I've trimmed down many CSS properties: &lt;code&gt;background&lt;/code&gt; is now &lt;code&gt;bg&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;border-color&lt;/code&gt; is &lt;code&gt;bc&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;margin-left&lt;/code&gt; is &lt;code&gt;ml&lt;/code&gt;, etc. Where I used to use &lt;code&gt;margin 0 0 2em&lt;/code&gt; (fewer characters than typing &lt;code&gt;margin-left 2em&lt;/code&gt;), I now use &lt;code&gt;mb 2em&lt;/code&gt;. The ability to abbreviate properties saves countless amount of typing, and is enough reason alone to use Stylus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here's the generated CSS by comparison:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;body.profile #content section.profile section.markdown aside {
  width: 320px;
  float: left;
  margin-left: -320px;
}
body.profile #content section.profile section.markdown aside h2 {
  font: bold 13px DIN, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif;
  line-height: 24px;
  text-transform: uppercase;
  -webkit-font-smoothing: antialiased;
  color: #555;
  letter-spacing: 1px;
  color: #ff006a;
  margin: 0 0 16px;
}
body.profile #content section.profile section.markdown aside ul {
  list-style: none;
}
body.profile #content section.profile section.markdown ul.process {
  margin-left: -320px;
}
body.profile #content section.profile section.markdown ul.process:after {
  display: block;
  clear: both;
  content: &quot;&quot;;
}
body.profile #content section.profile section.markdown ul.process li {
  float: left;
  margin: 0 0 1px 1px;
  list-style: none;
}
body.profile #content section.profile section.markdown ul.process li p {
  padding: 16px;
  margin: 0;
  width: 127px;
  height: 127px;
  font: bold 13px DIN, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif;
  line-height: 24px;
  text-transform: uppercase;
  -webkit-font-smoothing: antialiased;
  color: #555;
  letter-spacing: 1px;
  color: #ccc;
  transition: all 0.15s ease;
  -webkit-transition: all 0.15s ease;
  -moz-transition: all 0.15s ease;
  -o-transition: all 0.15s ease;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;dl class='comparison'&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Stylus Character Count&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;&lt;span&gt;337&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;CSS Character Count&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;&lt;span&gt;1369&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Convinced yet?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have only grazed the surface of what's possible with the immense power of Stylus, and it makes me excited about what I'll playing with in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Built with git, vi, and Jekyll.</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/hello-jekyll"/>
   <updated>2011-03-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/hello-jekyll</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've migrated this site to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. It seems much easier to use than ExpressionEngine. Of course, you have to be comfortable in text editors and SSH. I can't stand textareas on the web anymore. It feels so slow and unwieldy. Developer notes follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;March 3rd: Why are post summaries so difficult to pull off? I might have to migrate to Nanoc instead. Update: for the meantime, I've decided to not use post summaries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Lightboxes fundamentally broken&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;March 4th: A bit of a tangent, but I'm finding that lightbox scripts are fundamentally broken. The popup windows don't respond to keyboard shortcuts, and images never show up until they're 100% loaded. I don't think script writers understand how nice it is to see part of an image as it loads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It lets you decided whether to finish loading or skip ahead to another picture. A loading GIF doesn't give any information at all, and just pisses people off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The popup effect also takes you out of the flow of the original article. Usually, a lightboxed image is in reference to something you're reading. But by clicking on it, you're effectively hiding the content for the picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's a pain, and that's why almost all power users open images in new tabs instead. Sure, it can get can confusing trying to link an image tab to what you're reading. But at least it doesn't obscure everything.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Intuition is Bullshit</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/intuition-is-bullshit"/>
   <updated>2010-09-04T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/intuition-is-bullshit</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a href=&quot;//oed.com&quot;&gt;OED&lt;/a&gt;, &quot;Intuition is the ability to acquire knowledge without inference or the use of reason.&quot; The &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intuition_(knowledge)'&gt;Wikipedia article&lt;/a&gt; states that intuition provides us with unjustifiable beliefs (a common ailment of the human brain) and its popularity in supernatural and New Age writings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With such dubious company, why are user experience engineers using &quot;intuitive&quot; to describe the ideal user interface? UX is a science, not an art. There’s no such thing as knowledge without inference or reason. Don’t update your landing page on a whim because it &quot;feels right&quot;. Interface changes need to be backed by hard data, not by your gut instincts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost everything your users do can be tracked, recorded, and graphed by numerous &lt;a href=&quot;//kissmetrics.com&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;//google.com/analytics&quot;&gt;dissemination&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;//mixpanel.com&quot;&gt;services&lt;/a&gt;. Don’t let your graphic designer make these decisions for you: start tracking.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Dropbox Tip No. 1</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/dropbox-tip-1"/>
   <updated>2010-07-05T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/dropbox-tip-1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Want your Vim configuration on another computer? Add this line to your &lt;code&gt;~/.exrc&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;source ~/Dropbox/.exrc
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t have a Dropbox account yet? Get your &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/referrals/NTQ3MDYyNDY5&quot;&gt;own now&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Drawar Bank Entry</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/drawar-bank"/>
   <updated>2010-04-22T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/drawar-bank</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bank mockup designed for &lt;a href=&quot;//www.drawar.com/forums/84/version2000--online-banking-statements/&quot;&gt;Drawar's Version2.001&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Safari&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the design only completely works in Safari. Such is life when developing on the bleeding edge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//v2.nylira.com/tumblr/posts/bank-safari-big.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//v2.nylira.com/tumblr/posts/bank-safari.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Drawar Bank rendered by Safari 4/Win&quot; title=&quot;Drawar Bank rendered by Safari 4/Win&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Firefox&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firefox 3.6+ gets most of the design correct. but has issues displaying the SVG graph and leaves unsightly white margins between actions. Webkit's gradient engine (which powers Safari and Chrome) considers borders part of the &quot;background area&quot; when it renders gradients. Firefox's Gecko engine does not. The discrepancy is quite frustrating when you try to use RGBA/HSLA borders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//v2.nylira.com/tumblr/posts/bank-firefox-big.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//v2.nylira.com/tumblr/posts/bank-firefox.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Drawar Bank rendered by Firefox 3.6/Win&quot; title=&quot;Drawar Bank rendered by Firefox 3.6/Win&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Chrome&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chrome has issues rendering all the CSS3 gradients. There's also noticeable color banding in Chrome's gradients, a flaw you don't see with Safari or Firefox. On the upside, Chrome's V8 Javascript engine blows every other browser out of the water when it comes to transitions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//v2.nylira.com/tumblr/posts/bank-chrome-big.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//v2.nylira.com/tumblr/posts/bank-chrome.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Drawar Bank rendered by Chrome 5/Win&quot; title=&quot;Drawar Bank rendered by Chrome 5/Win&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;View the &lt;a href=&quot;//v2.nylira.com/p/bank&quot;&gt;bank mockup&lt;/a&gt; live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Sass&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used this as an opportunity to learn more about &lt;a href=&quot;//sass-lang.com/&quot;&gt;Sass&lt;/a&gt;. Sass is a powerful abstraction layer for CSS. It supports variables, mixins, simple arithmetic, and basic looping functions. Writing Sass is essentially writing CSS without brackets or semicolons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the difference in size between the &lt;a href=&quot;//v2.nylira.com/p/bank/css/screen.css&quot;&gt;screen.css&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;//v2.nylira.com/p/bank/css/sass/screen.sass&quot;&gt;screen.sass&lt;/a&gt; files. screen.css is 675 lines long and weighs in at 22.6 KB. screen.sass is 439 lines long and weighs in at 10.1 KB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How is this possible? Most of Sass's power comes from mixins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;// here's a simple example
=border-radius($r: 5px)
  border-radius: $r
  -webkit-border-radius: $r
  -moz-border-radius: $r

// call it in screen.sass
+border-radius

// outputs this in screen.css
border-radius: 5px;
-webkit-border-radius: 5px;
-moz-border-radius: 5px;

// if you want to change the border radius, it's simple
+border-radius(20px)

// outputs
border-radius: 20px;
-webkit-border-radius: 20px;
-moz-border-radius: 20px;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It certainly saves a lot of tedious and repetitive typing. This is only the tip of the iceberg, too. Take a look at my default &lt;a href=&quot;//v2.nylira.com/p/bank/css/sass/_mixins.sass&quot;&gt;mixins.sass&lt;/a&gt; file for more examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;A minor gripe&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only issue I have with Sass is that its compiling speed isn't as fast as I would like. I'm used to saving my CSS file and then reloading my browser to instantly see my changes. With Sass playing middleman, it can take another second before the changes are reflected in the browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this has piqued your interest, check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://sass-lang.com/&quot;&gt;official Sass website&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Acorn</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/acorn"/>
   <updated>2010-04-02T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/acorn</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Acorn homepage redesign. &lt;a href=&quot;http://flyingmeat.com/acorn&quot;&gt;Acorn&lt;/a&gt; is a Mac image editing program developed by Flying Meat Inc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://v2.nylira.com/p/acorn/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://v2.nylira.com/tumblr/posts/acorn.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Analog Turk</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/analog-turk"/>
   <updated>2010-03-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/analog-turk</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Spurred on by &lt;a href=&quot;http://37signals.com/svn/posts/2229-sortfolio-uses-amazons-mechanical-turk&quot;&gt;SvN's post&lt;/a&gt; about the Amazon Mechanical Turk, this is how I would do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://v2.nylira.com/p/turk&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://v2.nylira.com/tumblr/posts/turk.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Ruby Programming Language</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/ruby-programming-language"/>
   <updated>2010-03-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/ruby-programming-language</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I redesigned the Ruby Programming Language homepage. Everything that you see--with the exception of &lt;a href=&quot;http://rubyidentity.org/&quot;&gt;the logo&lt;/a&gt;--consists of just two text files. Cascading stylesheets have come a long way since 1999.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal for the design was to make a monochromatic &amp;amp; image-less layout look visually striking and pretty. I think I've mostly succeeded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to say that I really love designing with just a text editor. Photoshop is unwieldy, cumbersome and utterly unsuited for most web design work. Sure, it still comes in handy for more illustration-heavy or textured websites. But for the majority of elegant and clean websites, a text editor works better and is magnitudes faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://v2.nylira.com/p/ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://v2.nylira.com/tumblr/posts/ruby.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Browser notes: this design looks best in Safari/Mac or Firefox 3.6+. I seemed to have broken Chrome's rendering engine with the gradient spammage. If you use IE or Opera, &lt;a href=&quot;http://v2.nylira.com/portfolio/ruby&quot;&gt;here's a picture&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://ruby-lang.org&quot;&gt;current ruby-lang.org&lt;/a&gt;, for comparison.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A Cleaner Slashdot</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/a-cleaner-slashdot"/>
   <updated>2010-03-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/a-cleaner-slashdot</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Slashdot's homepage is rather overwhelming. It certainly works well enough on a functional level, but I think it can be done better. This is my attempt to bright things up. Their &lt;a href=&quot;http://slashdot.org&quot;&gt;current website&lt;/a&gt;, for comparison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://v2.nylira.com/p/slashdot&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://v2.nylira.com/tumblr/posts/slashdot.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>
