<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Nylira Articles</title>
 <link href="http://nylira.com/en/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://nylira.com"/>
 <updated>2011-03-16T22:11:51+01:00</updated>
 <id>http://nylira.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Peng Zhong</name>
   <email>peng@nylira.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Responsive Design & Fluid Grids</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/fluid-grids"/>
   <updated>2011-04-05T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/fluid-grids</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Responsive design is about saving time by making flexible elements that can be reused across multiple devices. Here are some tips I've learned while building a &lt;a href=&quot;http://nylira.com/en/projects/#guildwork&quot;&gt;100% fluid site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Make Use of &lt;code&gt;box-sizing: border-box&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the default box model, adding a &lt;code&gt;1px border&lt;/code&gt; to two floats with %-based widths (e.g., 30% and 70%) breaks the layout. Your layout is now now &lt;code&gt;100% + 4px&lt;/code&gt; wide, which is annoyingly unhelpful. Likewise with adding em-based padding. At this point, most practical coders will sigh and add a internal wrapper &lt;code&gt;div&lt;/code&gt; with the border they want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While adding another &lt;code&gt;div&lt;/code&gt; is a fine (albeit hacky) solution, there's a cleaner way to do it. &lt;code&gt;box-sizing: border-box&lt;/code&gt; is a CSS3 property that fixes the box model for these use cases. Instead of adding padding and borders to the width of the box, it subtracts the same amounts from the space inside of the box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create this mixin in your &lt;a href=&quot;http://nylira.com/stylus-the-revolutionary-successor-to-css&quot;&gt;CSS preprocessor of choice&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;box-sizing(n = border-box)
  -webkit-box-sizing: n
  -moz-box-sizing: n
  box-sizing: n
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you can do the following to your heart's content:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#announcement
  border-box()
  width 40%
  float left
  border 1px solid #ddd
  padding .75em 1em
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it will only ever be 40% wide. Nice, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Any catches?&lt;/strong&gt; While &lt;code&gt;box-sizing&lt;/code&gt; is a CSS3 property, all browsers which support CSS2.1 will support &lt;code&gt;box-sizing: border-box&lt;/code&gt;. That's every browser except IE6/7.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;There's more to the world than &lt;code&gt;float: left&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the early days of CSS-based design, floats were all we had to achieve creative, tableless layouts. They are--and have always been--a hacky and buggy approach, but they've also been the best tools we've had. Most designers have a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stockholm_syndrome&quot;&gt;Stockholme syndrome&lt;/a&gt; relationship with CSS floats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Float-based layouts are fragile, prone to breaking, and require content clearing in most cases. Don't even try to do vertical alignment with variable-height floats. You'll need Javascript for that. The finicky nature of floats makes them ill-suited for the flexible, %-based world of web applications. What other options are there?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;code&gt;display: inline-block&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Useful for more than horizontal layout menus, &lt;code&gt;display: inline-block&lt;/code&gt; can be used in many situations in place of floats. Along with the contents of table cells, inline blocks can be vertically aligned, which leads to intriguing layout possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One caveat to inline blocks is that whitespace in HTML matters. If there's a space between two &lt;code&gt;display: inline-block&lt;/code&gt; elements, it will render on the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inline blocks are supported by all browsers except IE6/7. There is &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.mozilla.com/webdev/2009/02/20/cross-browser-inline-block/&quot;&gt;a hack available&lt;/a&gt; for IE6/7 support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;code&gt;display: table-cell&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most designers who learned CSS in the days of XHTML validation and web standards instinctively cringe away from anything related to tables. However, the property &lt;code&gt;display: table-cell&lt;/code&gt; does not imply any sort of relation between the content and tabular data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using &lt;code&gt;display: table-cell&lt;/code&gt; turns an element's display type into a &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;td&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, the original &lt;code&gt;box-sizing: border-box&lt;/code&gt; element. &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;td&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;s will automatically stretch to fill the available horizontal space. It's a great way to create columns of both variable width and height. Take for example an image next to a column of text. This is possible to do with floats, but when you introduce percentage-based padding, you save time with &lt;code&gt;display: table-cell&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using &lt;code&gt;display: table&lt;/code&gt; will turn all of an element's direct descendants into &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;td&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; types. If you're making consistent use of this, consider taking another look at your data: perhaps a real table is in order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Display table/table-cell is supported by all browsers except IE6/7.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Alignment issues?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you're using a CSS reset, you'll most likely encounter alignment issues using either &lt;code&gt;inline-block&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;table-cell&lt;/code&gt;. There's no need to panic. &lt;a href=&quot;http://meyerweb.com/eric/tools/css/reset/&quot;&gt;Eric Meyer's Reset CSS&lt;/a&gt; sets all elements to &lt;code&gt;vertical-align: baseline&lt;/code&gt;. That means elements of unequal heights will sit on a baseline instead of hanging from the top like floats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to fix it?&lt;/strong&gt; For &lt;code&gt;display: inline-block&lt;/code&gt;, you'll need to set its parent element to &lt;code&gt;vertical-align: top&lt;/code&gt;. For &lt;code&gt;display: table-cell&lt;/code&gt;, you'll need to set it to &lt;code&gt;vertical-align: top&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Avoid Dependency Hell&mdash;VirtualBox Your Projects</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/sandbox"/>
   <updated>2011-03-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/sandbox</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As I wrote &lt;a href=&quot;/en/profile&quot;&gt;on my profile&lt;/a&gt;, I manage a separate VirtualBox image for every project I do. What are the benefits of doing so?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Why Virtualize?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avoid dependency hell.&lt;/strong&gt; Ever come back to a project 2-3 months later, and not be able to run it because you've already upgraded your libraries to new versions? Debugging these scenarios always take a lot of trial and error. This won't happen anymore if you freeze the entire development environment along with the project code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Write once, run everywhere&lt;/strong&gt; VirtualBox images are extremely portable. VirtualBox can run on every major operating system, which means you can concievably work anywhere. If you develop on a Windows machine and want to collaborate with someone on OS X, you may run into problems with versioning. If both of you run VirtualBox, the problems all disappear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No more debugging development environments for your developers.&lt;/strong&gt; Related to the point above. Have someone joining your project? Instead of handing them a lengthy and error-prone installation guide, just give them a copy of your VirtualBox image. This saves a ridiculous amount of time and gets them up to speed with zero issues. This benefit of VirtualBox goes up the more contributers you have on your project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ubuntu is closer to a production environment.&lt;/strong&gt; While not exactly the same, a Ubuntu minimal install is much closer to your production server than either Windows or OS X. You'll be able to solve OS-specific issues early, so your live deployment will be certain to go without a hitch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Preconceived Doubts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Isn't system performance severely degraded with virtualization?&lt;/strong&gt; This really depends on what you're working on. For standard web development and design tasks, a virtualized Ubuntu is more than enough power. I'm running this on a 13&quot; MacBook Air with 1.86 GHz Core 2 Duo, and I've never had a problem with performance. Compiling might be a bit slower than you're used to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But it's such a waste of hard drive space!&lt;/strong&gt; Disk space is cheap these days.  My laptop has a 120 GB HD. That's probably less storage space than most of you are running. Also, installing with the Ubuntu Minimal CD image means you only install only the basic building blocks of the OS, and download what you need through apt-get. My freshly installed images weigh in 1.5 GBs each. Not bad, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doesn't it take a long time to setup your dev environment over and over?&lt;/strong&gt; Okay, you've got me there. The actual process of installing Ubuntu doesn't take very long, but getting the right packages and plugins can take a little while. Of course, most of this time is either downloading or compiling, so you're not actually stuck at the computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doesn't this take a lot of system memory?&lt;/strong&gt; This is a valid point. If you have under 2 GBs of RAM, performance will definitely be severely degraded with the disc swaps happening every transaction. I've never done virtualization with anything less than 4 GBs, but--then again, my Ubuntu images run just fine with 512mb of allotted RAM each. I have two images running at any one time, along with Chrome and Photoshop, and performance has been fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Barebones How-To&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interested in setting up a virtual image? Download these first:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Latest version of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.virtualbox.org/wiki/Downloads&quot;&gt;VirtualBox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://help.ubuntu.com/community/Installation/MinimalCD&quot;&gt;Ubuntu 10.10 64-bit Minimal CD&lt;/a&gt; (15.6MB)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An FTP program--I recommend &lt;a href=&quot;http://panic.com/transmit/&quot;&gt;Transmit&lt;/a&gt; for OS X, &lt;a href=&quot;http://filezilla-project.org/&quot;&gt;FileZilla&lt;/a&gt; otherwise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Install VirtualBox.&lt;/strong&gt; Create a new virtual machine with the default settings for a Ubuntu 64-bit guest OS. 512 MB of ram and 8 GBs of disk space is usually enough. If you have hard drive space to spare, I suggest increasing it to 20 GB. It's possible to increase the virtual disk size later, but it's a pain in the ass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Select your new virtual disk and open &quot;Settings.&quot;&lt;/strong&gt; With the Settings window open, click the Network button, and select the Adapter 2 tab. Enable the adapter and choose 'Host-only Adapter' from the dropdown menu. This is the first step in giving your host OS access to Ubuntu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boot up the new virtual disk.&lt;/strong&gt; Select the Ubunut Minimal CD .iso you downloaded earlier. Ubuntu is straightfoward to install. When it's done, login with your new username and password. The first command you should run is &lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install openssh-server&lt;/code&gt;. This will allow SSH and SFTP connections from your host OS to the new guest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Using either vi or nano, open&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;sudo vi /etc/network/interfaces&lt;/code&gt;. Add the following lines to the bottom of the file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;auto eth1
iface eth1 inet static
  address 192.168.56.101
  netmask 255.255.255.0
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Save and exit. Run these commands in the console:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo /etc.d/init/networking restart
sudo ifdown eth1
sudo ifup eth1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You're done. At this point, you should be able to SSH into your new virtual machine from the host OS, or mount the virtual drive with your FTP program.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Stylus, the Revolutionary Successor to CSS</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/stylus-the-revolutionary-successor-to-css"/>
   <updated>2011-03-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/stylus-the-revolutionary-successor-to-css</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;About a month ago, &lt;a href=&quot;http://learnboost.github.com/stylus&quot;&gt;Stylus&lt;/a&gt; was released, to little fanfare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's rapidly become my favorite web development tool. Cleaner and more flexible than &lt;a href=&quot;http://sass-lang.com/&quot;&gt;Sass&lt;/a&gt;, Stylus is by far the best CSS preprocessor in the wild. If you're unfamiliar with preprocessors, just imagine adding variables, functions, and simple arithmetic to CSS. While the additions may seem daunting to beginners, these advanced abstractions are desperately needed by maintainers of complex stylesheets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stylus syntax strips away all colons, semicolons, brackets and most parentheses from regular CSS script. The stark simplicity and elegance of it reminds me of Lisp. What's more amazing is that Stylus will also accept regular CSS syntax in the same file, reducing possible friction between multiple contributers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here's a sample of Stylus, a bit of code that powers this very site:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;section.markdown
  aside
    col 4
    ml - c4
    h2
      alt-font()
      color anchor
      mb m2
    ul
      ls none

  ul.process
    ml -4c
    clear()
    li
      float left
      mar 0 0 1px 1px
      p
        pad m
        mar 0
        square c4 - m2 - 1px
        alt-font()
        color #ccc
        transition()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You'll notice that I've trimmed down many CSS properties: &lt;code&gt;background&lt;/code&gt; is now &lt;code&gt;bg&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;border-color&lt;/code&gt; is &lt;code&gt;bc&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;margin-left&lt;/code&gt; is &lt;code&gt;ml&lt;/code&gt;, etc. Where I used to use &lt;code&gt;margin: 0 0 2em;&lt;/code&gt; (fewer characters than &lt;code&gt;margin-bottom: 2em;&lt;/code&gt;), I now use &lt;code&gt;mb m2&lt;/code&gt;. The ability to abbreviate properties saves countless amounts of typing, and is reason enough to use Stylus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here's the generated CSS by comparison:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;body.profile #content section.profile section.markdown aside {
  width: 320px;
  float: left;
  margin-left: -320px;
}
body.profile #content section.profile section.markdown aside h2 {
  font: bold 13px DIN, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif;
  line-height: 24px;
  text-transform: uppercase;
  -webkit-font-smoothing: antialiased;
  color: #555;
  letter-spacing: 1px;
  color: #ff006a;
  margin: 0 0 16px;
}
body.profile #content section.profile section.markdown aside ul {
  list-style: none;
}
body.profile #content section.profile section.markdown ul.process {
  margin-left: -320px;
}
body.profile #content section.profile section.markdown ul.process:after {
  display: block;
  clear: both;
  content: &quot;&quot;;
}
body.profile #content section.profile section.markdown ul.process li {
  float: left;
  margin: 0 0 1px 1px;
  list-style: none;
}
body.profile #content section.profile section.markdown ul.process li p {
  padding: 16px;
  margin: 0;
  width: 127px;
  height: 127px;
  font: bold 13px DIN, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif;
  line-height: 24px;
  text-transform: uppercase;
  -webkit-font-smoothing: antialiased;
  color: #555;
  letter-spacing: 1px;
  color: #ccc;
  transition: all 0.15s ease;
  -webkit-transition: all 0.15s ease;
  -moz-transition: all 0.15s ease;
  -o-transition: all 0.15s ease;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;dl class='comparison'&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Stylus Character Count&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;&lt;span&gt;337&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;CSS Character Count&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;&lt;span&gt;1369&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Convinced yet?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have only grazed the surface of what's possible with the immense power of &lt;a href=&quot;http://learnboost.github.com/stylus/&quot;&gt;Stylus&lt;/a&gt;, and it makes me excited about what I'll playing with in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Built with git, vi, and Jekyll.</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/hello-jekyll"/>
   <updated>2011-03-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/hello-jekyll</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've migrated this site to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. It seems much easier to use than ExpressionEngine. Of course, you have to be comfortable in text editors and SSH. I can't stand textareas on the web anymore. It feels so slow and unwieldy. Developer notes follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;March 3rd: Why are post summaries so difficult to pull off? I might have to migrate to Nanoc instead. Update: for the meantime, I've decided to not use post summaries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Lightboxes fundamentally broken&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;March 4th: A bit of a tangent, but I'm finding that lightbox scripts are fundamentally broken. The popup windows don't respond to keyboard shortcuts, and images never show up until they're 100% loaded. I don't think script writers understand how nice it is to see part of an image as it loads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It lets you decided whether to finish loading or skip ahead to another picture. A loading GIF doesn't give any information at all, and just pisses people off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The popup effect also takes you out of the flow of the original article. Usually, a lightboxed image is in reference to something you're reading. But by clicking on it, you're effectively hiding the content for the picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's a pain, and that's why almost all power users open images in new tabs instead. Sure, it can get can confusing trying to link an image tab to what you're reading. But at least it doesn't obscure everything.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Intuition is Bullshit</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/intuition-is-bullshit"/>
   <updated>2010-09-04T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/intuition-is-bullshit</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a href=&quot;//oed.com&quot;&gt;OED&lt;/a&gt;, &quot;Intuition is the ability to acquire knowledge without inference or the use of reason.&quot; The &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intuition_(knowledge)'&gt;Wikipedia article&lt;/a&gt; states that intuition provides us with unjustifiable beliefs (a common ailment of the human brain) and its popularity in supernatural and New Age writings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With such dubious company, why are user experience engineers using &quot;intuitive&quot; to describe the ideal user interface? UX is a science, not an art. There’s no such thing as knowledge without inference or reason. Don’t update your landing page on a whim because it &quot;feels right&quot;. Interface changes need to be backed by hard data, not by your gut instincts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost everything your users do can be tracked, recorded, and graphed by numerous &lt;a href=&quot;//kissmetrics.com&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;//google.com/analytics&quot;&gt;dissemination&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;//mixpanel.com&quot;&gt;services&lt;/a&gt;. Don’t let your graphic designer make these decisions for you: start tracking.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Dropbox Tip No. 1</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/dropbox-tip-1"/>
   <updated>2010-07-05T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/dropbox-tip-1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Want your Vim configuration on another computer? Add this line to your &lt;code&gt;~/.exrc&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;source ~/Dropbox/.exrc
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t have a Dropbox account yet? Get your &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/referrals/NTQ3MDYyNDY5&quot;&gt;own now&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Drawar Bank Entry</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/drawar-bank"/>
   <updated>2010-04-22T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/drawar-bank</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bank mockup designed for &lt;a href=&quot;//www.drawar.com/forums/84/version2000--online-banking-statements/&quot;&gt;Drawar's Version2.001&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Safari&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the design only completely works in Safari. Such is life when developing on the bleeding edge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//v2.nylira.com/tumblr/posts/bank-safari-big.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//v2.nylira.com/tumblr/posts/bank-safari.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Drawar Bank rendered by Safari 4/Win&quot; title=&quot;Drawar Bank rendered by Safari 4/Win&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Firefox&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firefox 3.6+ gets most of the design correct. but has issues displaying the SVG graph and leaves unsightly white margins between actions. Webkit's gradient engine (which powers Safari and Chrome) considers borders part of the &quot;background area&quot; when it renders gradients. Firefox's Gecko engine does not. The discrepancy is quite frustrating when you try to use RGBA/HSLA borders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//v2.nylira.com/tumblr/posts/bank-firefox-big.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//v2.nylira.com/tumblr/posts/bank-firefox.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Drawar Bank rendered by Firefox 3.6/Win&quot; title=&quot;Drawar Bank rendered by Firefox 3.6/Win&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Chrome&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chrome has issues rendering all the CSS3 gradients. There's also noticeable color banding in Chrome's gradients, a flaw you don't see with Safari or Firefox. On the upside, Chrome's V8 Javascript engine blows every other browser out of the water when it comes to transitions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//v2.nylira.com/tumblr/posts/bank-chrome-big.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//v2.nylira.com/tumblr/posts/bank-chrome.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Drawar Bank rendered by Chrome 5/Win&quot; title=&quot;Drawar Bank rendered by Chrome 5/Win&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;View the &lt;a href=&quot;//v2.nylira.com/p/bank&quot;&gt;bank mockup&lt;/a&gt; live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Sass&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used this as an opportunity to learn more about &lt;a href=&quot;//sass-lang.com/&quot;&gt;Sass&lt;/a&gt;. Sass is a powerful abstraction layer for CSS. It supports variables, mixins, simple arithmetic, and basic looping functions. Writing Sass is essentially writing CSS without brackets or semicolons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the difference in size between the &lt;a href=&quot;//v2.nylira.com/p/bank/css/screen.css&quot;&gt;screen.css&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;//v2.nylira.com/p/bank/css/sass/screen.sass&quot;&gt;screen.sass&lt;/a&gt; files. screen.css is 675 lines long and weighs in at 22.6 KB. screen.sass is 439 lines long and weighs in at 10.1 KB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How is this possible? Most of Sass's power comes from mixins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;// here's a simple example
=border-radius($r: 5px)
  border-radius: $r
  -webkit-border-radius: $r
  -moz-border-radius: $r

// call it in screen.sass
+border-radius

// outputs this in screen.css
border-radius: 5px;
-webkit-border-radius: 5px;
-moz-border-radius: 5px;

// if you want to change the border radius, it's simple
+border-radius(20px)

// outputs
border-radius: 20px;
-webkit-border-radius: 20px;
-moz-border-radius: 20px;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It certainly saves a lot of tedious and repetitive typing. This is only the tip of the iceberg, too. Take a look at my default &lt;a href=&quot;//v2.nylira.com/p/bank/css/sass/_mixins.sass&quot;&gt;mixins.sass&lt;/a&gt; file for more examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;A minor gripe&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only issue I have with Sass is that its compiling speed isn't as fast as I would like. I'm used to saving my CSS file and then reloading my browser to instantly see my changes. With Sass playing middleman, it can take another second before the changes are reflected in the browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this has piqued your interest, check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://sass-lang.com/&quot;&gt;official Sass website&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Acorn</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/acorn"/>
   <updated>2010-04-02T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/acorn</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Acorn homepage redesign. &lt;a href=&quot;http://flyingmeat.com/acorn&quot;&gt;Acorn&lt;/a&gt; is a Mac image editing program developed by Flying Meat Inc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://v2.nylira.com/p/acorn/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://v2.nylira.com/tumblr/posts/acorn.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Analog Turk</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/analog-turk"/>
   <updated>2010-03-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/analog-turk</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Spurred on by &lt;a href=&quot;http://37signals.com/svn/posts/2229-sortfolio-uses-amazons-mechanical-turk&quot;&gt;SvN's post&lt;/a&gt; about the Amazon Mechanical Turk, this is how I would do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://v2.nylira.com/p/turk&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://v2.nylira.com/tumblr/posts/turk.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Ruby Programming Language</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/ruby-programming-language"/>
   <updated>2010-03-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/ruby-programming-language</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I redesigned the Ruby Programming Language homepage. Everything that you see--with the exception of &lt;a href=&quot;http://rubyidentity.org/&quot;&gt;the logo&lt;/a&gt;--consists of just two text files. Cascading stylesheets have come a long way since 1999.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal for the design was to make a monochromatic &amp;amp; image-less layout look visually striking and pretty. I think I've mostly succeeded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to say that I really love designing with just a text editor. Photoshop is unwieldy, cumbersome and utterly unsuited for most web design work. Sure, it still comes in handy for more illustration-heavy or textured websites. But for the majority of elegant and clean websites, a text editor works better and is magnitudes faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://v2.nylira.com/p/ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://v2.nylira.com/tumblr/posts/ruby.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Browser notes: this design looks best in Safari/Mac or Firefox 3.6+. I seemed to have broken Chrome's rendering engine with the gradient spammage. If you use IE or Opera, &lt;a href=&quot;http://v2.nylira.com/portfolio/ruby&quot;&gt;here's a picture&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://ruby-lang.org&quot;&gt;current ruby-lang.org&lt;/a&gt;, for comparison.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A Cleaner Slashdot</title>
   <link href="http://nylira.com/a-cleaner-slashdot"/>
   <updated>2010-03-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://nylira.com/a-cleaner-slashdot</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Slashdot's homepage is rather overwhelming. It certainly works well enough on a functional level, but I think it can be done better. This is my attempt to bright things up. Their &lt;a href=&quot;http://slashdot.org&quot;&gt;current website&lt;/a&gt;, for comparison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://v2.nylira.com/p/slashdot&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://v2.nylira.com/tumblr/posts/slashdot.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>
